Fairfield Business Papers Ms B34
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Fairfield Business Papers
1785-1994
Ms B34
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.5 Linear feet (1 Box)
This artificial collection is made up of items from various Fairfield businesses.
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
This collection contains items from various Fairfield businesses starting in the late 1700's up through present day. Biographical information specific to some of the companies can be found further in the finding aid.
Accruals note
Additional accruals are anticipated with the last addition being made in November 2011.
Scope and Contents note
This is an artificial collection made up of small collections from various Fairfield businesses. The collection is arranged by company. Companies represented include the Fairfield Trust Company, Wolverine Motor Works, Fairfield Post Office, W. O. Burr Corporation, The Great A & P Company, McKesson & Robbins, the Fairfield Rubber Company, the Kennel Food Supply Company and others.
Andrew Tucker Studios (Fairfield, Conn.) .; Fairfield Philatelic Society (Fairfield, Conn.) .; Fairfield Post Office (Fairfield, Conn.) .; Fairfield Rubber Company (Fairfield, Conn.) .; Fairfield Trust Company (Fairfield, Conn.) .; Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company.; Howard Johnson Co..; J.M. Wilson & Bro. (Fairfield, Conn.) .; John E. Boyle (Fairfield, Conn.).; Kennel Food Supply Company.; McKesson and Robbins, inc. .; McKesson Corp. .; Mercurio (Fairfield, Conn.).; Musica, Philip, 1884-1938; Pepperidge Farm, inc. .; Perry's Pharmacy (Fairfield, Conn.) .; W.O. Burr Corporation .; Wolverine Motor Works.; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Advertising.; Business--United States.; Commercial catalogs.; Correspondence.; Fairfield--Burning by the British, 1779; Merchants; Postmasters; Price lists.; Stock certificates
- McKesson & Robbins
  Biographical/Historical note
  McKesson & Robbins, established in 1833 in New York City, was a successful national pharmaceutical company. They were bought in 1924 and resold in 1926 retaining the original name. The new buyer, F. Donald Coster, also known as Philip Musica, moved the manufacturing department to Fairfield, CT into a former gas mask factory. Coster, accused of fraud, committed suicide in 1938. The company continued under new leadership until 1967 when it was again bought and called the McKesson Corporation. The Fairfield building was resold and razed in 1989. For more information, a copy of The Road to Market, 1833-1958 is available in the library (658.7 M156r). It chronicles the history of the company and the pharmaceutical industry.
  - Miscellaneous items, 1933; Folder A
    - Letter to Roclock Inc. Southport from F. Donald Coster, 1933
    - Photocopies of news articles about Frank Coster and the company, 1956
    - Photograph of factory, circa 1940
    - Enlarge copy of photograph of company baseball team poster, 1932
  - Catalogues and books, Folder A1; 5 items
    - McKesson & Robbins price list, 1908
      Related Archival Materials note
      A similar 1891 price list is available in the library (658.87 m156).
      Custodial History note
      Gift of Robert Ometer, 1973
    - McKesson & Robbins cost book, n.d.
      General note
      Accession number 87.July.4
- Fairfield Rubber Company
  - Insurance specifications, 1889-1926; Folder B
    This was accession number L82.D.2
    The Fairfield Rubber Company was later known as the I. E. DuPont De Nemours Company.
- The Kennel Food Supply Company
  The Kennel Food Supply Company was started in 1890 by Simon C. Bradley. It was located on Mill River below Sturgis Road Bridge. The plant was destroyed by fire in 1917 & rebuilt in the same year. The company was among the first to sell canned dog food. It was closed in 1959 and operations moved to Ohio.
  - Miscellaneous items, Folder C; 5 items
    - List prices, 1929
    - Pamphlet
    - Invoice, 1927
    - Blotter
    - Envelope, 1929
- Miscellaneous businesses
  - Items, Folder D
    - John E. Boyle, druggist and chemist--calendar, 1925
      Donated by Richard Perry in 1945.
    - Howard Gray, antique building material dealer--letterhead
    - Howard Johnson's menu, circa 1950
    - Mercurio, food shop--advertisement, circa 1933
    - Pepperidge Farm--anniversary card
    - Perry's Pharmacy--advertisement
    - Andrew Tucker Studios--advertisement
    - J. M. Wilson & Bro., dealers in ice and wood--blank bill
    - C. O. Jelliff Mfg. Corp.--letter to Elizabeth Banks, 1959
    - Account book pages from unidentified Fairfield shop, circa 1785; 2 items
      Accession number L2006.25
- The Great A & P Company
  The A & P was located in Fairfield on the Post Road.
  - Menus, 1936-1937; Folder E; 3 items
- The W. O. Burr Corporation
  Items in this series are from accession number L94March8.
  - W. O. Burr Corporation Minute Book, 1961-1982; Folder F
  - Miscellaneous items, Folder G
    - Appraisal report of property, 1973
    - Map, 1935
    - Budget for beach property, n.d.
  - Property appraisal by Scott, Fitton & Co. including 14 house listings and land maps, Folder H
- Fairfield Post Office
  - Miscellaneous items, Folder I
    - Photocopy of letter re: moving post office, 1861
    - Postmaster's certificate of appointment, 1892 (Oversize Manuscript Drawer IX)
    - Letter re: Greenfield Hill post office, 1923
    - Lists of postmasters in Fairfield County, n.d.
    - First day cover, 200th anniversary of the Burning of Fairfield, issued 1979 by the Fairfield Philatelic Society
      This is from accession number L1999.18.
    - Inauguration program for new postmaster, 1994
- Wolverine Motor Works, Inc.
  - Stock certificate, 1960; Folder J
- Fairfield Trust Company
  The Fairfield Trust Company opened for business May 20, 1920 in the former house of Dr. William Donaldson, located at the corner of Post Rd. and Old Post Rd. In 1927, on the same site, it built a new structure designed specifically as a bank. In 1937 the bank became a branch of the Bridgeport Trust Company.
  These materials were donated by the estate of Helen Dunbar Venman on September 28, 1998. She served as the bank's assistant treasurer.
  This donation also included photographs of Dr. Donaldson's house on the Post Road which stood where the bank is now; these are filed under the street address in the photograph collection. Other materials related to the trust Company are located in the advertising collection.
  - Miscellaneous items, Folder K
    - Quarterly statements, 1932, 1936
    - History brochure, 1937
    - Stockholders' letter, 1937
    - Blank letterhead